SUCHITHA RAMACHANDRAPURAPU

+91-9182130430 ♦ survasuchitha@gmail.com ♦ Vijayawada, India

OBJECTIVE

Experienced Developer adept in all stages of SDLC. Knowledgeable in user experience, user interface design, development, testing, and debugging processes. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set, writing clean code, team collaboration, Documentation, Deployment, Version Control. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

SKILLS

 \bullet HTML5

• CSS

• Bootstrap

Javascript

• React JS

• Git

• Node Package Manager(NPM)

• NPM Scripts

• React Hooks

• Redux

• JSON

AJAX

• Figma

• Adobe Photoshop

MS Office

• Wordpress

Webflow

WORK EXPERIENCE

Team Lead 2023 - 2024

Elpizo Technologies Pvt Ltd., Viayawada

- Built reusable React components and front-end libraries for future use.
- Managed application state using Redux, Context API, and other state management libraries.
- Integrated RESTful APIs to fetch and display dynamic data within the applications.
- Led and mentored web design team in mastering WordPress development and crafting professional websites utilizing no-code solutions like WordPress and Webflow alongside building responsive websites from scratch using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Assistant Systems Engineer Trainee

2021 - 2023

Tata Consultancy Services, Mumbai

- Enhanced application functionality to service requests for new feature implementations, ensuring efficient trade processing workflows by collaborating with business stakeholders and translated the requirements into basic code using Visual Basic and Oracle PL/SQL.
- Supported diverse environments by providing functional support across Staging, User Acceptance Testing (UAT), and Production environments, ensuring smooth application operation.
- Offered support to team members, promoting continuous learning and professional development.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

2017 - 2021

Shri Vishnu Engineering College for Women, Bhimavarm.

LINKS

Github: suchi-291

LinkedIn: suchitha-r Portfolio: suchitha R